novica.com 2018-09-08

# Customer Service | NOVICA

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [www.novica.com](https://www.novica.com/).

Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we will notify you of:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the web site
  2. The organization collecting the information
  3. How the information is used
  4. With whom the information may be shared
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under NOVICA's control
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact our customer service department by email at [service@novica.com](mailto:service@novica.com). NOVICA wholeheartedly respects your privacy. The sole owner of all personal information collected at this site is NOVICA, and NOVICA will NEVER rent or sell your personal information to any third party. When you visit [www.novica.com](https://www.novica.com/), we collect some basic information in order to enhance your experience navigating the website. The information collected and stored by NOVICA includes products purchased, feedback from visitors, location data, logs and other communication data, information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system and browser type. This information is then aggregated with other pieces of information to improve our site and make your experience on the site as valuable and efficient as possible. Pages of the site may use devices that permit us to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics. 

If you purchase an item online from NOVICA, interact with [www.novica.com](https://www.novica.com/) by submitting feedback, opt to receive the NOVICA Journal by email or write a product review, you provide us with personally identifiable information including your first and last name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, and email address. While your credit card information is also collected at the time of purchase, only the last four digits are stored on NOVICA's server. Credit card information is sent directly to DigiCert's secure server, and that is where it is safely held. Because NOVICA collects personal information through a secure server that features the latest encryption technology, you can be assured that none of your information will be viewed by anyone outside of NOVICA and DigiCert (please see the Credit Card Security section for more information). Furthermore, all shipping labels are pre-printed at NOVICA's regional offices, so none of your personal information is held or stored by any of the shipping companies that are used to deliver NOVICA's orders. 

The personally identifiable information you provide to NOVICA will be used to process your order. You will only be contacted by NOVICA if you place an order or if there is a problem with your order. By placing an order you will automatically receive the NOVICA Journal by email, but you can always change your email preferences if you wish to be removed from our list by simply emailing us at [remove@novica.com](mailto:remove@novica.com). You may also update or change the personal information NOVICA has collected by sending an email to [service@novica.com](mailto:service@novica.com). This page will be immediately updated should there be any changes to NOVICA's Privacy Guarantee. 

Third party advertising companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. These third party cookies do not collect personally identifiable information. Cookies are bits of information that allow a website server to associate you with the specific products that you have added to your shopping cart. Web Beacons are electronic files used to track your navigation a website or collection of sites the completion of transactions, submittal of applications and browsing behavior.

While you are shopping, NOVICA collects non-personal information about our website traffic and usage patterns from technology such as Cookies and Web Beacons. We use cookies to keep track of the items that you have placed in your shopping cart, and to provide enhanced online display advertising tailored to your interests. To opt out of this advertising provided directly by NOVICA, click here. If your cookies are turned off, you will not be able to shop online with NOVICA as the system will fail to associate you with any items that you have added to your cart. However, you may still place your order by telephone. We recommend that you turn your cookies on while shopping at NOVICA, as this will allow for a much more enjoyable and worry-free shopping experience. Click here for information on making sure that your cookies are turned on. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit [www.novica.com](https://www.novica.com/). These companies may use information about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>.

We may share your personally identifiable information and non-personal information, including your name, address, email address and any transactions you conduct on our website or offline with us with a trusted third party advertising partner and its service providers in order to deliver tailored advertising to you that match your interests when you visit our website. Our trusted advertising partners will anonymize the data that we transfer via secure encryption ensuring that no one else will receive your personally identifiable information and that the anonymous data cannot be reverse engineered to reveal any consumer's identity.

You may opt-out of the use of your information for tailored advertising purposes. To learn more about the use of this information or to choose not to have this information used by our third-party advertising partner by opting out please visit the Network Advertising Initiative by [clicking here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). **If you delete your Cookies, use a different browser, or buy a new computer, you will need to renew your opt-out choice**. 

NOVICA does not knowingly collect any personal information from children.

Privacy policy last updated on June 8, 2012.
